Jefferson Patterson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1946-1978 (Box 40-67)
  - Uruguay, 1956-1967, (2 folders)
  - "U-V" miscellaneous, 1958-1975, (2 folders)
  - Wilberforce University, Wilberforce, Ohio, 1959-1960
  - Woodward, Robert F., 1958-1974 (Box 66)
  - Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, Dayton, Ohio, 1964-1977
  - "W" miscellaneous
    - 1952-1974, (7 folders)
    - 1975-1977 (Box 67)
  - Yale University, New Haven, Conn., 1958-1971, (3 folders)
  - "Y" miscellaneous, 1953-1977
  - Zgorzelski, Ladislao, 1958
  - "Z" miscellaneous, 1958-1974
- Speeches and Writings File, 1923-1971 (Box 67-72)
  Correspondence, speeches, book drafts, poetry and miscellaneous writings, notes and related material, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and therein chronologically.
  - Speeches, 1952-1959, 1970, undated (Box 67)
  - Writings
    - Books
      - Correspondence, 1956-1971, (2 folders)
      - Diplomatic Duty and Diversion (1956)
        - General, 1955-1961, undated, (4 folders)
        - Notes and related material, 1923-1952, undated, (8 folders) (Box 68)
        - Various drafts, undated, (7 folders) (Box 69)
      - Diplomatic Terminus: An Experience in Uruguay (1962) (Box 70)
        - General, 1961-1963
        - Marked copy, undated
        - Notes and related material, 1950-1951, undated
        - Various drafts, undated, (4 folders)
      - Family Portraits (1967), 1967, undated
      - "Flashbacks and Reflections" (unpublished), 1970, undated, (5 folders) (Box 71)
      - Outside and In, 1939-1941 (1944), 1944, 1952, undated
    - Miscellaneous items, 1929-1966, undated, (2 folders)
    - Notes, 1942, undated (Box 72)
    - Poetry, undated
- Miscellany, 1894-1977 (Box 72-84)
  Correspondence, memoranda, financial and legal papers, notes and recollections, student notebooks, appointment books, address books, passports and visas, medical and military papers, certificates, calling cards, scrapbooks, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material and therein chronologically.
  - Academic file (Box 72)
    - General, 1900-1917, undated
    - Notebooks, undated
      - Business statistics
      - English
      - German and French
      - History
        - American, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 73)
        - English
      - International law and geography
      - Law
        - Agency II
        - Bills
        - Contracts
        - Corporations (Box 74)
        - Criminal, (2 folders)
        - Pleadings
        - Property, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 75)
      - Sales
  - Address books, undated
  - Ambassador and diplomatic service file
    - General
      - 1922-1931, (3 folders)
      - 1932-1948, (8 folders) (Box 76)
      - 1949-1958, undated, (5 folders) (Box 77)
    - Passports and visas, 1922-1944, 1950-1958, (2 folders)
    - United Nations Special Committee on the Balkans
      - Correspondence, 1949-1952, (2 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1949-1952, undated
      - Notes and recollections, 1950-1952, undated, (4 folders) (Box 78)
      - Official documents
        - 1947-1950, (5 folders)
        - 1951-1952, (4 folders) (Box 79)
  - Appointment books
    - 1926-1954, (2 folders)
    - 1955-1977, (2 folders) (Box 80)
  - Calling cards
    - 1921-1930, 1941-1945, (2 folders)
    - Undated (Box 81)
  - Certificates, 1920, 1930-1959
  - Financial and legal papers
    - General, 1921, 1927, 1941-1958, undated, (2 folders)
    - Journals
      - 1926-1940, (2 folders)
      - 1940-1949, (2 folders) (Box 82)
    - Ledgers
      - 1913-1933
      - 1934-1945 See Oversize
      - 1934-1950 See Oversize
  - Medical papers, 1 919, 1940-1950, undated (Box 83)
  - Military papers, 1916-1919, 1923-1933, 1944, undated, (3 folders)
  - Miscellaneous, 1912-1952, undated, (2 folders)
  - Printed matter, 1912-1917, 1926, 1933-1946, (2 folders)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Cigar band wrappers, undated
    - General
      - 1894-1904
      - 1901-1922, (4 folders) (Box 84)
- 2018 Addition, 1909-1981 (Box 85-87)
  Correspondence, family papers, invitations, notes and jottings, photographs, poetry, scrapbooks, newspaper clippings, printed matter, and other material relating to Patterson's personal and professional activities.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Correspondence, 1909, 1941-1967, undated, (6 folders) (Box 85)
  - Family papers, 1910, 1926-1949, 1963-1965, undated, (3 folders)
  - Miscellany, 1949-1955, 1975
  - Notes, jottings, and poetry, 1955-1977, undated, (2 folders)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 86)
    - Book, Diplomatic Duty and Diversion (1956), 1964-1981
    - Chronological file
      - 1955-1969, (6 folders)
      - 1970-1977, (2 folders) (Box 87)
- Oversize, 1934-1950 (Box OV 1-OV 2)
  Oversize ledgers organized and described according to the series, boxes, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Miscellany (Box OV 1)
    - Financial and legal papers
      - Ledgers
        - 1934-1945 (Container 82)
        - 1934-1950 (Container 82) (Box OV 2)